Register of the America First Committee Records, 1940-1942
Hoover Institution Archives
- MISCELLANEOUS OFFICE FILES
  - Card Indexes (Box 304.)
    - Illinois, members
      - Rockford (Box 323.)
        - Contributors
        - Members
    - Indiana, members
    - Iowa, members (Box 324.)
    - Maryland, members
    - Massachusetts (Box 325.)
      - Springfield
        - Original membership applications
        - Members (Box 326.)
      - General, members
    - New England, members
    - Michigan, members (Box 327.)
    - New Mexico, members (Box 328.)
    - New York
      - Buffalo
      - Jamaica (Box 329.)
      - Long Island City
      - Astoria
      - Queen Village, Bellmire, Bellerose (Box 330.)
      - Hollis
      - Maspeth
      - Forest Hills--Kew Gardens
      - Laurelton
      - Springfield Gardens
      - St. Albans
      - Corona
      - South Ozone Park (Box 331.)
      - Richmond Hill
      - Woodhaven
      - Belle Harbor Bayshore
      - Howard Beach
      - Broad Channel
      - Arverne
      - Stewart Manor
      - Little Neck
      - Far Rockaway
      - Rockaway Park
      - Glendale
      - Ridgewood
      - Rockeville Center (Box 332.)
      - Long Island, miscellaneous
      - Ozone Park
      - Brooklyn
      - Woodside
      - Sunnyside
      - Yonkers (Box 333.)
      - Ardsley
      - Averill Park
      - Bedford Village
      - Bronxville
      - Crestwood
      - Dobbs Ferry
      - Jackson Heights (Box 334.)
      - Elmhurst
      - Flushing
      - Bellevue
      - Bayside
      - Miscellaneous (Box 335.)
    - Ohio, members
    - Virginia, members (Box 336.)
    - Washington (state), members
    - Wisconsin, members
  - Maps of Congressional Districts in Southern California, 1941 (Box 337.)
  - Sheet Music of A.F.C. and other patriotic songs
  - Handbills and campaign material
  - Press release of A.F.C.
  - Notebook of founding documents and minutes of the directors' meetings
  - Financial Records
    - Lists of contributors by state
    - Lists of large contributors
    - List of contributors
    - Auditor's Report, September 1941-February 1942
    - Taxes
      - Gift tax returns
      - Federal Old Age Benefits
      - State of Illinois return
    - Bank statements and passbooks
    - Summary statement of cash receipts and disbursements inception to March 1941
    - Balance sheet statements, 1940-41
    - Trial balance draft, ledger
    - Day journal of receipts and disbursements, 1941-1942. 3 volumes
- OVERSIZE FILE
  - Receipts for contributions, numbers 11-3342, 1941. 2 volumes (Box 339.)
  - Receipts and disbursements, 1940-1941. 2 volumes (Box 340.)
  - Bulletins sent to local chapters, January-June 1941
  - Newspaper clippings and campaign material, Chicago. 1 scrapbook
  - Receipt and disbursements, 1941-1942. 2 volumes (Box 341.)
  - Newspaper clippings (Box 342.)
    - South Bend, Indiana Chapter
    - Los Angeles, California Chapter
    - Hartford, Connecticut Chapter
    - New York Chapter
  - Form letters, pamphlets, and campaign buttons (Box 343.)
  - Newspaper clippings, Rockford, Illinois Chapter
  - Accounts payable and accounts receivable, 1940-1942. 2 volumes (Box 344.)
  - Newspaper clippings, Colorado Chapter (Box 345.)
  - Newspaper clippings and campaign material, Chicago Chapter (gift of Fred L. Adair). 1 scrapbook
- Sound recordings
  26 phonorecords, mostly undescribed
  - Sound recording of Charles Lindbergh speech, 1941 April 23; Use copy reference number: 42001_a_0000144_a01 (Record cabinet)
    This speech was delivered at Manhattan Center and broadcast by WMCA in New York. Disc reads "No. 2976."
  - Sound recording of interview with Brigadier General Robert E. Wood, 1941 July 25; Use copy reference number: 42001_a_0002839 (Record cabinet)
    Wood describes the activities of the America First Committee. He says both the committee and its opponents credit it with keeping America out of war at least two times in the past. The conversation also touches on Charles Lindbergh, Secretary Knox, accusations of Nazi funding, Wood's prediction for the end of the war, America going off the gold standard, the stand of the committee on national defense, future American foreign policy, British ambassadors, and the American economy. The general believes America cannot be invaded. He says the committee members are doing their civic duty to try to keep America out of the war. The interview was recorded at the Biltmore Hotel in Los Angeles, California, on 2 discs
  - Sound recording of Senator Burton K. Wheeler speech, undated; Use copy reference number: 42001_a_0002977 (Record cabinet)
    A speech by the Montana senator in the lead-up to America's involvement in World War II. He criticizes the government for stockpiling war supplies such as caskets. He describes the war as Europe's war. Criticizing House Bill 1776, he says it will sever the independence America won from the United Kingdom in 1776 and will allow the president to wage an undeclared war in defense of a foreign entity. Following, Burton criticizes how the government has transferred military arms to Britain even without H.R. 1776. However, he feels private citizens' financial aid to other countries is each citizen's private right. He notes that the non-interventionalist foreign policy is not fashionable despite its root in the Founding Fathers' rhetoric. He cites a poll that over eighty percent of the American population opposes a declaration of war.
  - Sound recording of Robert E. Wood speech: Our Foreign Policy, 1940 October 26; Use copy reference number: 42001_a_0002978 (Record cabinet)
    General Wood discusses American involvement in the war between the United Kingdom and Germany. Beginning by calling the terms interventionalist and isolationist non-descriptive, he mentions the issues on which the population is united. After analyzing the conflict between the two European countries, he believes there is no danger of invasion of the United States even if Germany is victorious. He argues this is true for a direct attack/invasion, attack from Central America, or from an air attack. He then criticizes some of the rhetoric used in the debate of American involvement, saying some of the "mudslinging...is no better than the Nazis." He believes American involvement in World War I was not worth the blood and money spent, and that the Treaty of Versailles laid the groundwork for Hitler's rise to power. Label reads: Oct. 26, 1940 CBS 10:15-10:30 P.M. E.S.T. "Our Foreign Policy" By General Robert E. Wood (Came up cut) Batten, Barton, Durstine & Osborn Chicago, Ill.